翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
The reason that our array-based lists are going to have a much faster Get operation is as follows.
基于数组的链表具有更快的 get 操作的原因如下
On a real computer these days, no matter how big your array is, say, it's 100 million items,
在一台真正的计算机上，不管你的数组有多大，比方说有一亿项
any of those items you can get at the same amount of time, constant time, and that time is fast.
你可以在相同的恒定时间内获取任何项，而且速度很快
So even if you want item number 50 million out of a huge array,
即使你想从一个巨大的数组中找出第5000万项
it grabs it immediately.
也会立刻得到
Now, that is not 100% always, always, always true.
这并不是百分之百正确的
Occasionally, if the array gets really big,
偶尔数组变得很大
it'll start getting pushed into slower parts of your computer's memory or even a disk drive.
它将开始被推入计算机内存中较慢的部分，甚至是磁盘驱动器
So there's a little bit of a caveat here,
所以这里有一个小小的警告
but for our purposes in 61B, whenever we're running our code, we'll almost, almost always be able to assume that this is true.
但是对于61B，每当我们运行代码，几乎总是能够假设这是真的
Now, if you're curious why it is,
如果你好奇为什么会这样
in 61C, we'll discuss that in more detail,
我们将在 61C 中更详细地讨论
but it's just a nice feature of hardware and the way operating systems interact with them.
这只是硬件和它与操作系统交互方式的一个好特点
So given that fact, we can now hope to make our array-based code much faster.
鉴于这一事实，我们现在可以希望使基于数组的代码更快
So ultimately, what we're trying to do here,
归根结底，我们在这里要做的是
and what we're going to do in the next few minutes
接下来几分钟要做的是
is whereas before we had this beautiful DList
以前我们有这个精美的 DList
that had these four operations, these two memory boxes, and this recursive list definition that the sentinel node pointed at,
它有这四个操作，这两个内存盒子，以及哨兵节点所指向的递归链表
now we're going to have the same exact operations
现在我们将进行同样的操作
and the same API or interface,
相同的 API 或接口
and now we're going to come up with an alternate way that involves using arrays.
现在我们要想出另一种方法，就是使用数组
So I'm going to write some code, and you can also do this, by the way.
我要写一些代码，顺便说一下，你也可以这样做
In fact, I think the best way you could possibly do this right now is to try and work without watching me,
实际上，我觉得你现在最好的办法就是试着不看我写
and then come and watch once you've given it a chance.
给自己一个机会后再来看
So if you look inside of the lecture code repository, which is linked from the website, you will see that there is a DIY folder.
如果你查看这个网站链接的课程代码库，会看到有一个 DIY 文件夹
So if you import that into IntelliJ,
把它导入 IntelliJ
or if you do it in Sublime or whatever,
或者 Sublime 之类的
you can start working on the code.
就可以开始编写代码了
Now, I'm going to do it in a folder called Live,
现在我选择一个名为 live 的文件夹
because this is going to be code that I'll push to the website you can look at later.
因为我会将这些代码推送到你稍后可以查看的网站
So I'm going to open up live, and do the usual project import thing that you saw in project two.
打开 live，执行在项目2中看到的常见项目导入操作
So I push next a bunch of times.
按了好几次 next
The code pops up.
代码弹出
And now we're ready to go.
准备好了
So here is the AList that we're going to fill in.
这就是我们要填写的 AList
And I've already got all the methods defined to save us some time.
我已经定义了所有的方法来节省时间
So what we're going to do is in our AList constructor,
我们要做的是在 AList 构造器中
we need to decide what memory boxes to set up.
决定要设置哪些内存盒子
So I know that I have a size method.
我知道有个 size 方法
So I'm definitely going to have at least size as an instance variable,
所以我肯定会将 size 作为实例变量
and I'm also going to need some kind of array.
还需要某种数组
So I'm going to do an integer-based array,
我要构造一个基于整数的数组
because int, integer items only for now.
因为目前只有整数项
And we'll make it generic later, just because that keeps things simple.
稍后会将其泛化，只是因为这会使事情变得简单
So for now, we're going to have an array called items.
现在我们将有一个名为 items 的数组
And so when we instantiate a list,
当实例化链表时
we're going have to say items equals new something.
写 items = new int[]
I'm going to pick some arbitrary size.
挑选任意大小
I'm going to pick 100, just because.
我选择100
And then I'm going to say that the size is also zero now.
size 现在是0
Now, we move on to Add Last.
转到 addLast
It's at the basics of our program.
这是我们程序的基础内容
So to figure out array Add Last, I'm actually going to do a little example here
为了写出 addLast，我要在这里做一个小例子
where I'm going to imagine that this is items.
我要把它想象成是项
So it's originally all a bunch of zeros,
初始化为0
and size is going to be zero.
size 也是0
That's when it starts.
这就是开始
And then as I add items, they're going to fill in here.
当我添加项目时，会填充到这里
So the first item I add, maybe items is--
所以我添加的第一项，可能是...
I do Add Last six and size increases to one.
添加6，size 加1
Then someone calls Add Last on nine, and then size increases to two.
再调用 addLast(9)，size 增加为2
And then someone calls Add Last and on minus 1, and now size is three.
再调用 addLast(-1)，现在 size 是3
And up here, I guess I'll annotate each one of these spots with the address,
在这里，我用地址注明每个地点
or with the-- sorry, not the address, but the index.
对不起，不是地址，是索引
And so right here, we now have a set of items.
所以这里有一些项
And when we call Add Last, then something good should happen.
当我们调用 addLast 时，就会有好事发生
So what's that thing?
什么好事？
Well, I'm going to observe that the next item I insert,
我观察到我插入的下一项
it's going to go into position three.
它将进入3号位置
So someone types in, or does Add Last two.
比如输入2
Some of it goes there.
就放在那里
And size increases to four, and so forth.
size 增加到4，以此类推
And I observe something very interesting, which is that--
我观察到一件非常有趣的事情，那就是...
so I'll write a couple sets of-- or a set of notes here,
我在这写一组笔记
which is that when it comes to doing Add Last, the next item we want to add will go into position size.
当调用 addLast 时，我们要添加的下一项将放到 size 位置处
Where's the next one go?
下一项去哪？
Position size.
size 位置
And so what I'm doing here is by working out this little example here,
通过这个小例子
and this is the kind of thing I do when I'm thinking about how I might implement a data structure--
这就是我在考虑如何实现数据结构时所做的事情
I just work out a small example--
我只是想出一个小例子
is I'm trying to abstract the pattern.
试着抽象这个模式
I'm trying to find, ultimately,
试图寻找，最终...
what it is that makes Add Last tick, or what should make it tick.
是什么让 addLast 得以运行
And what I'm actually coming up with here is a set of invariants.
实际上我在这里想出的是一组不变量
So this is a-- and we talked about invariants in a previous lecture.
我们在上一节课中讲过不变量
They are things that are always true about our data structure.
对于我们的数据结构，它们总是正确的
And so here, Add Last tells us that the next item we're going to add will go into position size.
在这里  addLast 告诉我们要添加的下一项将进入 size 位置
What good is that, that little observation?
这个小小的观察有什么用呢？
Well, that means my code is very simple then.
那意味着我的代码非常简单
I say that Items Size equals x
只需 items[size] = x
I know that the thing I want to insert is going to go into position size, and also I need to increase size by one.
我知道我想要插入的东西将进入 size 位置，还需增加 size
So another invariant I'll mention is that when it comes to size, the number of items in the list should be size.
我要提到的另一个不变量涉及到 size，链表中的项数应该是 size
How about Get Last?
getLast 呢？
Well, if we wanted to get the last item, what is that item?
如果我们想要最后一项，那是什么？
Which one is it?
是哪一个？
This one, two.
这个，2
And so we imagine-- I don't know. I'm going to imagine if I add something else.
假设我们再添加点其他东西
I don't know, if someone adds zero, actually,
比如有人添加0
then I increase size to five.
size 增加到5
And that's going to be the last item.
这将是最后一项
So I can imagine maybe I make a little note here.
也许我可以在这里做个记号
Nah, I don't know.
不
I don't like that notation.
我不喜欢这个记号
So this is the item I want to return.
这就是我要返回的东西
And so when it comes to invariants,
所以当涉及到不变量时
we can say Get Last.
我们可以说 getLast
The item we want to return is in position size minus one.
我们要返回的项的位置是 size-1
Oh, spell check. That's nice.
拼写错了
And so when it comes to Get Last,
当谈论 getLast 时
we can just write return items size minus one.
只需写 return items[size-1]
Having this invariant up here makes the code very easy.
这个不变量使得代码非常简单
When it comes to Get, that one's super easy.
get 方法超级简单
We just need to return the item.
只需要 return items
And when it comes to writing the size method,
编写 size 方法时
we just return the size variable.
只需返回 size 变量
So we're not going to go through this code
我们不会再过一遍这段代码
and exhaustively test it or anything.
并对其进行详尽的测试
That's the construction I came up with, and it should be fine.
这是我想出的结构，应该没问题
Now, actually, I provided a test method here,
实际上，我在这提供了 Test 方法
or some test code you can actually run on your own implementation, but I won't do it right now.
你可以在自己的实现上运行测试代码，但我现在不会这样做
So let's look at the code I came up with.
让我们来看看我想出的代码
The AList class here, well, notice it's very similar to what I just came up with on the fly.
这里的 AList 类，注意它和我刚才临时想出来的非常相似
There are a couple of differences.
有几个不同之处
One is this private keyword.
一个是 private 关键字
So you'll notice in my code, I didn't actually put a specifier here, and that's a common mistake whenever a programmer is new.
你会注意到在我的代码中
我实际上没有在这里放一个标识符，这是程序员新手经常犯的错误
That actually, you might wonder, what does it mean to not have any keyword.
你可能会想，没有任何关键字意味着什么
We'll talk about that in a couple of weeks.
我们将在几周后讨论这个问题
But what we-- instead, it's better practice to put private,
但是现在更好的做法是放置 private
because that ensures that no outsider is going to edit our code.
这样可以确保没有外人编辑我们的代码
So that's something we might have forgotten.
这是我们易忘的东西
Another thing I did here in this code
我在这段代码中做的另一件事
is you'll notice that the constructor is all on one line.
就是构造函数都写在一行内
And I have a semicolon separating these two statements.
我用分号分隔这两个语句
So this is better style.
这是更好的风格
You might wonder why I did this here.
为什么要在这里这么做
The hint for you is this is a lecture on the internet.
提示你，这是一场互联网上的讲座
And the answer is simply that I don't have the vertical space.
答案很简单，垂直空间不够了
So I'd say this is bad style, even though it is actually possible in Java.
这是一种糟糕的风格，尽管在 Java 中可行
So that's the code.
这就是代码
Now, note also I've written out the invariants that we put in our code before.
现在还要注意，我已经写出了之前在代码中放入的不变量
And these invariants are really nice to have.
这些不变量真的很不错
Now, when you're writing code, chances are you're probably not going to sit there and write out all your invariants,
当你写代码时，很可能不会坐在那里写出所有的不变量
but maybe that's something you like to do.
但也许这是你喜欢做的事情
It's one of those things that's kind of like safety equipment,
这种东西有点像安全设备
where if you have the invariants actually written out,
如果你把不变量写出来
you can consult them as you're going.
你可以边走边看
It kind of just depends on the style of programmer that you are.
这在某种程度上取决于你是什么样的程序员
So some programmers really actually like having invariants.
一些程序员非常喜欢拥有不变量
And actually, there's a whole field of computer science
实际上，有一个完整的计算机科学领域
where you try and prove that your programs are actually mathematically correct,
你需要试着证明你的程序在数学上是正确的
and invariants are a tool you can use to do that.
不变量是实现这一点的工具
Now, maybe you prefer to just having--
也许你更喜欢...
sorry. You might just prefer to have little drawn out examples like that.
你可能更喜欢这样的小例子
And that could be fine, too.
这也很好
But invariants is maybe the most mathy way of thinking about programming.
但不变量也许是对编程最数学化的思考方式
So that's it for our basic operations.
这就是我们的基础操作
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
We'll move onto the lead operations next.
接下来将讨论高级操作